rewire.news 2018-06-29

# Privacy Policy - Rewire.News

_Last updated May 25, 2018_

**Privacy Policy**

_Rewire.News_ wants to ensure that visitors to our site understand what information we gather about them, how we use it, and how we work to protect it.  By using our website, and/or signing up for services such as our newsletter, you consent to information practices outlined in our Privacy Policy.

**Information Collection**

We track how our visitors use this site so that we can see what people like and don’t like. We also analyze and aggregate information about use patterns and may share the aggregated data with our consultants, funders and others involved with _Rewire.News_. We may also collect personal information about you via registration for newsletters, commenting, making donations, interaction with external social networks and platforms, remarketing and behavioral targeting, displaying content from external platforms, and other areas. Where you have an opportunity to supply information about yourself, you may choose not to provide requested information, but in such cases you may not be able to use certain functions on this website.

We will not release your name, email address or any other personal information to anyone outside _Rewire.News_ without your consent, unless we are under a legal order to do so or there is an emergency involving danger to a person or property.

If you chose to provide your personally identifiable information for the purposes of a third-party contest, survey or newsletter, your consent shall be deemed to be given for the release of your personally identifiable information with regard to that third party only, in addition to _Rewire.News_. Only authorized _Rewire.News_ employees or consultants are allowed access to personal information about you. Any employee or consultant who violates our privacy and security policies is subject to disciplinary action.

We occasionally have service contractors, third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates, and/or joint ventures that perform functions on our behalf, including but not limited to credit card processing and website hosting. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of the data. They are restricted from using or altering this data in anyway other than to provide the requested services to _Rewire.News_. In addition, we may always share, disclose, and transfer all information, postings, and any and all other personal and non-personal information we have collected to a successor-entity in the case of the sale of the assets of _Rewire.News_ , corporate reorganization, merger, change in control, or other similar transaction.

Remember that any information you share in public areas, such as the _Rewire.News_ comments area, becomes public and therefore this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you choose to make public. We encourage visitors to _Rewire.News_ to be cautious about what they disclose and that they do not post any personal information that they expect to keep private. Personally Identifiable Information is information that can be used to contact you or determine your specific identity.  If other information is linked to this information, it also becomes Personally Identifiable Information.

**Use and Disclosure of Anonymous Information**

Anonymous Information is any information other than Personally Identifiable Information, including aggregate information derived from Personally Identifiable Information.

_Rewire.News_ may use this information:

To improve the _Rewire.News_ website and service, to monitor traffic and general usage patterns, and for other general business purposes.

To inform publishers as to what content is appealing to readers, to inform _Rewire.News_ stakeholders of the usage habits or characteristics of the interested audience, and to advise potential donors so that they may better understand _Rewire.News_ ’ user base.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a website’s servers and stored on your computer. Each website can send its own cookies to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) most browsers only permit a website to access the cookies that the same website has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites.

_Rewire.News_ may use cookies to identify you as a repeat visitor or customer of the website, to maintain session information for logged in users, and to track usage trends and patterns in order to better understand and improve areas of our website.

_Rewire.News_ has no control over whether and how any sites we link to use cookies that originate from their website. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, but you may not be able to take full advantage of our site’s features.

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf.  These companies may employ cookies and action tags to measure advertising effectiveness. All computers and servers on the internet use IP addresses to recognize and communicate with each other. We collect IP addresses to administer and analyze our site and report aggregate, non-personal information (such as how many visitors we have). When you call up our site on your computer, our servers enter the IP address of that computer into a log. To maintain our users’ anonymity, we do not associate IP addresses with records containing personal information.

We do not and cannot use cookies or IP address tracking to retrieve personal information from your computer.

View our [Cookie Policy](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/35574190/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy") for more specific information about exactly what cookies _Rewire.News_ uses and why.

**Security**

_Rewire.News_ employs a number of security methods designed to prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure correct use of information. Your personal data will be stored within a database that is located behind a firewall for added security.

No data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be secure.  As a result, while we try to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. We are not liable for the illegal acts of any third party.

We use SSL to encrypt all web sessions to help protect user privacy and data.

**Links to Other Sites**

_Rewire.News_ provides links and pointers to websites maintained by other organizations. _Rewire.News_ provides these links as a convenience to users, but it does not operate or control such sites. _Rewire.News_ also disclaims any responsibility for the information on those sites and any products or services offered there, and cannot vouch for the privacy policies of such sites. _Rewire.News_ does not make any warranties or representations that any linked sites, or this site, will function without error or interruption, that defects will be corrected, or that the sites and their servers are free of viruses and other problems that can harm your computer.

**Opt Out**

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

**Children**

_Rewire.News_ is not directed to children (persons under the age of 13), and we do not knowingly collect, either online or offline, Personally Identifiable Information from children. If you believe that we have received information from a person under 13, please contact us via our [contact form](https://rewire.news/contact-us) or in writing at _Rewire.News_ , 7315 Wisconsin Ave., Ste. 400W, Bethesda, MD 20814, and we will take appropriate action.

## **The Rights of Users**

You may exercise certain rights regarding your data processed by the _Rewire.News_.

You are entitled to broader protection standards may exercise any of the rights described below. In all other cases, you may inquire with _Rewire.News_ to find out which rights apply to you.

In particular, if you you are entitled to broader protection standards, you have the right to do the following:

  * **Withdraw their consent at any time.**  Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
  * **Object to processing of their Data.**  Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.
  * **Access their Data.**  Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
  * **Verify and seek rectification.**  Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
  * **Restrict the processing of their Data.**  Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.
  * **Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.**  Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
  * **Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.**  Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User’s consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.
  * **Lodge a complaint.**  Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

### **Details About the Right to Object to Processing**

Where personal data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in _Rewire.News_ or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by _Rewire.News_ , you may object to such processing by providing a ground related to your particular situation to justify the objection.

You must know that, however, should your personal data be processed for direct marketing purposes, you can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether _Rewire.News_ is processing personal data for direct marketing purposes, you may refer to the relevant sections of this document.

### **How to Exercise These Rights**

Any requests to exercise your rights can be directed to _Rewire.News_ through contact details provided at the end of this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by _Rewire.News_ as early as possible and always within one month.

## **Applicability of Broader Protection Standards**

While most provisions of this document concern all users, some provisions expressly only apply if the processing of personal data is subject to broader protection standards.

Such broader protection standards apply when the processing:

  * concerns the personal data of users who are in the EU and is related to the offering of paid or unpaid goods or services, to such users;
  * concerns the personal data of users who are in the EU and allows _Rewire.News_ to monitor such behavior taking place in the EU.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

_Rewire.News_ may change its privacy policy from time to time.  If we make any changes regarding disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information to third parties, we will post notice of the new policy on our home page.

**Disclaimers and Limitations of Liability**

ALTHOUGH WE TAKE REASONABLE STEPS TO PREVENT THE INTRODUCTION OF VIRUSES, WORMS, OR OTHER DESTRUCTIVE MATERIALS AND PROGRAMS TO OUR SITE, WE DO NOT GUARANTEE OR WARRANT THAT OUR SITE OR MATERIALS THAT MAY BE DOWNLOADED FROM OUR SITE ARE FREE FROM SUCH DESTRUCTIVE FEATURES. WE ARE NOT LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES OR HARM ATTRIBUTABLE TO SUCH FEATURES. WE ARE NOT LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, LOSS OR INJURY BASED ON ERRORS, OMISSIONS, INTERRUPTIONS OR OTHER INACCURACIES IN OUR SITE, NOR FOR ANY CLAIM, LOSS OR INJURY THAT RESULTS FROM YOUR USE OF THIS SITE OR YOUR BREACH OF ANY PROVISION OF THIS AGREEMENT.

**Questions and Requests  
**

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy or our use of your information, or you would like to make a request specific to your data, please see our [Contact Us page](https://rewire.news/contact-us).
